Let's see how the depth first search algorithms work with an example of undirected graph.
We have solved the exercise the previous exercises about the verdict to the crash.
Let's see how the depth first, the DFS works in another example.
We have used an own direct to the graph with five vertices.
So we are going to create further.
Vertices is here.
You're.
Zero, one, two, three and four zero is connected with two zero is connected to three zeros, connected
to one.
One connected to two and two connected to four.
No.
We have, as I told you, we have the visited.
And their stack.
OK.
If we start from the following the numerical order, we should start from zero.
Otherwise, you can start from any vertex if there is no condition.
If you said to you in the interview or that university exams that you have to follow the numerical order,
you should start from zero.
OK.
So in this case, we start from zero.
Now.
Zero.
What if we were all standing at zero?
What are the possible, what are the adjacent vertices is what are the possibility to move from zero?
We can visit one.
We can visit two and we can visit City.
OK.
But since we are using and following their depth first algorithm, so we are and the numerical order
dominates, so we are going to go through zero del one.
So we are passing to one since it is and then numerical order, so the visited ones.
So till now, we have visited the vertex.
Logically, we have visited zero because we started from it and one two three we have visited only one.
OK.
No one since zero has already visited, so we visit that number one instead.
No, we are on one.
The Stack Zero is connected to one zero, is connected to two and zero connected to three, but two
and the three are not visited.
So we've put them into the stack.
So here we have the stack.
See you at two and the three.
OK, Vertex two has that is has an unvisited adjacent vertex in is four.
OK.
So we add that to the top of the stack and visit it, since it is the visit, that one is due.
So we in the stack, we add it, we move from one to two.
Do we visit ED and we add it to the visitor numbers and the visited vertices?
OK.
We remove it from the stack.
Vertex two has the arm visited adjacent Vertex four.
So we add that to the top of the stack.
So at least two by four.
OK.
This is how we move like this?
No.
Vertex two has the unvisited adjacent Vertex four, so we add that to the top of the stack and visit
it.
OK, so we visit it, we go from two to four.
OK.
This is at the top of the stack, and we remove it from four for has any connection.
No.
So we remove it from the stack.
Till now, we still have in the Stack City, so we visit number three after we visit the last element
city.
It does not have.
Here is the three cell.
We visit it and we remove it from that stack after we visit the Element City.
It does not have any unvisited adjacent no cell.
We have completed their depth first search algorithm.
In terms of complexity, that depth first algorithm has a space, complexity and time complexity.
So that time complexity here, time complexity.
For the US is represented in forum of all two V plus e, where V is the number of nodes or vertices
is vertices is.
No, and he is the number of at just number of edges.
OK.
The space complexities, space complexity.
Is all due to fee where we as the number of number of vertices.
OK, so this is the time complexity and this is the space complexity for the.